so let's look at the problem of
multicore and many core power and
performance the problem is this we have
one core let's say it can spend a
hundred watts which is the power budget
for the entire chip and that power of
the one core is really some sort of a
constant times the voltage squared times
the frequency of the core let's say that
we get a hundred watts consumption when
we set the voltage and the frequency
such that we can operate at 3.8
gigahertz now let's say that we get two
cores in that case each gets half the
power budget of the chip the per core
power in the two core case is one half
of the single course power so we need to
reduce the voltage and frequency such
that we get one half of the power
remember that voltage can be reduced in
proportion to frequency so the frequency
at which we can run a coroner to core
system is going to be cubic root of one
half times the frequency at which we can
operate a single core in a single core
system which is this frequency and that
ends up being 0.8 approximately times f1
or three gigahertz so as you can see if
we now use only one of these cores we
get to run it at three gigahertz as
opposed to 3.8 gigahertz that we could
get here so this is noticeably slower